# **Jeffrey Heller**

Web Developer

Silver Spring, Maryland 201-819-5315 heller.jeffrey@gmail.com https://github.com/Jheller11

Full-stack web developer with a passion for learning and finding creative solutions to the most complex problems. Experienced team leader who believes in using effective communication and planning to meet organizational goals.

# **Skills**

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Ruby | Python | MongoDB | Express | Node | Git | Github | React

# **Experience**

**General Assembly** 

**Student - Web Development Immersive** 

Washington, DC

January 2018 - May 2018

Full-time three month program focused on front and back end development including almost 500 hours of classes, labs, projects, and code review. Covered development and coding as an individual and in collaboration with a small team. The projects that I completed for this course are:

- Pyramids: A Tower of Hanoi inspired game (HTML/CSS/JavaScript)
- Liverpool-Links: A full stack application where supporters can post links to relevant team news or content as well as view match highlights and other videos. (MongoDB, Node, Express)
- Global Cup: A solution for managing local youth or recreational sports leagues. Have your users/coaches register their teams and list rosters of players. (React, MongoDB, Node, Express)

#### Sughrue Mion, PLLC

Washington, DC

August 2008 - January 2018

Manager - Client Teams Department

(March 2016-January 2018)

- Managed a team of 20+ specialists responsible for over \$4 million in annual revenue.
- Worked with firm management to budget, plan, and implement new procedures designed to increase productivity and accuracy.
- Acted as first point of contact for two of the firms largest clients and elevated issues to attorneys when necessary.
- Prepared and filed new U.S. patent applications and handled all subsequent correspondence with U.S. Patent and Trademark Office.

### **Patent Prosecution Specialist**

(November 2008-March 2016)

- Prepared and filed new patent applications, including provisional and non-provisional utility applications, design applications, and U.S. National Phase entry of PCT applications.
- Prepared Information Disclosure Statements in accordance with client and attorney instructions.
- Reviewed office actions from the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office and drafted correspondence for reporting to clients.

# **Education**

#### **General Assembly**

Web Development Immersive Washington, DC January 2018 - May 2018 American University School of Public Affairs Bachelor of Arts in Justice, Law & Society May 2008